Davin Stirling

I am an experienced IT professional with over 12 years experience working in both the UK and NZ tech industries, ranging from service desk & application support to systems analysis & design. I have recently pivoted into software development, completing a 4 month intensive programming bootcamp with iO Academy and gaining my scrum master certification. I have a particular interest in backend technologies and am keen to build on my experience with LAMP and MERN stacks.

https://davin2020.github.io

https://github.com/davin2020

davin.stirling+jobs@gmail.com +44 7434 701 274 Bath, UK Entitled to work in UK & NZ

PROJECTS

Knowsy: Social Media Site - MERN

API Code http://bit.lv/ghSocialAPI Live http://bit.lv/ghSocialAPI Live http://bit.lv/socialmdemo

As a scrum team of 4 we decided on the MERN stack with GraphQL for the API calls. We mostly did pair programming and I chose to work on the backend API, where I was heavily involved in researching and creating the GraphQL queries and mutations. I also integrated the front and backend repos so they could talk to each other.

Robot Stores: Ecommerce Store - LAMP

Code http://bit.ly/ghStores Live https://bit.ly/ghStores

I volunteered as Scrum Master for this project sprint and facilitated our team to create a detailed architecture plan, using my previous OO experience. We later adjusted the plan after reviewing the SOLID principles. Using the LAMP stack, we decided on the Hydrator Entity design pattern in PHP, with HTML, CSS and Bootstrap. I pair programmed to create some PHP classes, and also peer reviewed colleagues code in GitHub. During sprint review I gave a non-technical overview of the site's architecture.

To Do App - PHP

Code https://bit.ly/GHDtodo
Live https://bit.ly/todoslim

After learning about MVC and PHP frameworks, we created a To Do app by cloning a Slim 4 repo and went through the architecture plan as a group. Working independently, I created CRUD functionality for the underlying MySQL database, using Routing, the Dependency Injection Container, Factories, Controllers and Views.

Jarver's Crypt: Maze Game - JavaScript

Code http://bit.ly/ghMaze Live https://bit.ly/jsmaze

As a scrum team of 8 people, we designed and created a maze game using JavaScript, HTML and CSS. I pair programmed to design and build the splash screen, and created the EventListeners to detect collisions. I also implemented changes after our tutor's code reviews in GitHub

SKILLS

LAMP

MERN

JavaScript including Express

Node.js & React

GraphQL API

RESTful APIs & Postman

MongoDB & Compass & Atlas

MySQL

PHP7 including PHPUnit, Slim

OOP, SOLID & MVC design principles

HTML5 & CSS3

Git & GitHub

Docker

Scrum/Agile

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Course – iO Academy, 2020

Certified Scrum Master – Agilify, 2020

Certificate in Applied Film-making & TV Production – NZ Film Academy, 2014

First Class BSc (Hons) in Computer Science, with IBM UK – University of Portsmouth, 2003

EXPERIENCE

Support Consultant

Fusion 5, NZ // Sep - Nov 2019

Learned about Ivanti ITSM and provided application support. Investigated, analysed and resolved issues experienced by internal staff. Deployed minor changes into test and production environments, eg adding form fields, updating email templates & business logic workflow, adjusting views etc

Field Services Engineer

WSP Opus // Nov 2018 - Sep 2019

Provided onsite and remote end user support to resolve issues and reduce backlog of 5,500 incidents following domain migration of mailboxes, users, assets, file servers, websites etc. Travelled to regional offices, performed pre and post migration checks and user support during migration. Collaborated with the IT team and fellow contractors to provide support. Successfully migrated 1,800 users and 2,100 assets within 6 weeks across 23 sites.

Service Desk Analyst

Plant and Food Research // Jul - Nov 2018 Watercare // Mar - Apr 2018 DDSIT // Mar 2013 - Jul 201

Web Developer Whyte Communications // Nov 2012 - Jan 2013

Technical DB Documentation Visionstream // Nov 2011 - Jun 2012

Senior Customer Service Agent Kaseya // Oct 2010 - Nov 2011

Technical Support (Level 2) Visionstream // Dec 2009 - Sep 2010

Technical Analyst Gen-i, NZ // Oct 2007 - May 2009

Volunteering and Travel

August 2005 - August 2007

Volunteered as a house builder in Thailand for a year following the 2004 tsunami, enabling local families to build 106 houses. Taught myself basic spoken & written Thai to improve communications between locals and volunteers. Managed a team of 15 people in the project manager's absence.

Technical Support (Level 3)

IBM Warwick, UK // Sep 2003 - Jun 2005

Worked shifts providing 24x7 support in an eCommerce Server Farm

Application Developer (Java)

IBM Portsmouth, UK // Sep 2001 - Sep 2003

Sole developer, responsible for the full life cycle design, development and deployment of a website to register staff for a conference, built using Java, JSPs & JDBC. Received an internal award for their "innovative web-enabled registration application, enabling reuse for other conferences". Mentored a junior developer, enabling him to customise the original website & deploy it for a different conference

Technical Resource

IBM UK // April - July 2001

INTERESTS

Avid traveller, visited 10+ countries in the 12 years in between various IT contracts while living in NZ

Attended 4 month filmmaking bootcamp in 2014, undertook industry work experience and later made various short films

Sci-fi tv shows

The design & architecture of almost everything from housing to software

Especially interested in tech that helps to improve people's lives via psychology